♪Wind♪
♪ الرياح ♪
♪Incidentally blows away fascinating whispers of love♪
♪ يضرب عرضا بيادق الحب الرائعة ♪
♪Whispers of love♪
♪ حراس الحب ♪
♪Sound the best with loyalty to the only valentine♪
♪ دق أفضل بالولاء إلى الوصية الوحيدة ♪
♪The prosperous life♪
♪ الحياة المزدهرة ♪
♪Is when we are together all year round♪
♪ هو عندما نكون معا على مدار السنة ♪
♪For the rest of my life♪
♪ لبقية حياتي ♪
♪All I want is a perfect love with you♪
♪ كل ما أريد هو حبك المثالي ♪
♪I'll remain elegant for you all my life♪
♪ سأبقى أنيقة لك طوال حياتي ♪
♪Giving you my love little by little♪
♪ إعطائك حبي شيئًا فشيئًا ♪
♪I care for you with every piece of my heart♪
♪ أنا أهتم بك في كل قلبي ♪
♪And I miss you every day and night♪
♪ وأنا أشتاق إليك كل ليلة ♪
♪I'll be loyal to you in the best years of my life♪
♪ سأكون مخلصا لك في أفضل سنوات حياتي ♪
♪Melting love with gentle smiles♪
♪ تميّز الحب بالأعمدة الحمقاء ♪
♪I won't be afraid of anything♪
♪ لن أشعر بالخوف من أي شيء ♪
♪And I won't change my heart for you♪
♪ لن أغيّر قلبي من أجلك ♪
=Jade's Fateful Love=
= حب اليشم المؤلم =
=Episode 9=
= الحلقة التاسعة =
The border has got chaotic again lately.
فقدت الحدود الفوضى مرة أخرى في الآونة الأخيرة
The Taxila Tribe of Dongyu
قبيلة التاكسيلا من دونغيو
keeps harassing our people on the border.
لا تنفك تتحرش بشعبنا على الحدود
I guess they'll pick another fight.
أعتقد أنهم سيختارون معركة أخرى
In this case,
في هذه الحالة
I'm afraid our foxy uncle will be impatient.
أخشى أن يكون عمنا الثعلب نفد صبره
The marriage thing is settled.
شيء الزواج يتم حله
There's no point in killing the Princess of Dongyu.
لا فائدة من قتل أميرة دونغيو
They will do something else
سوف يفعلون شيئا آخر
to start a war again.
لبدء حرب مرة أخرى
Without a war,
بدون حرب
they couldn't have command
لا يمكن أن يكون لديهم قيادة
over politics and military.
و
What do you think we should do, Shiyu?
ما رأيك أن علينا أن نفعل يا شيو؟
Conserve strength
حافظ على القوة
and fight back in full force.
للقتال بقوة كاملة
Things in Yingzhou and Taizhou go smoothly.
الأمور في ينغ تشو وتاتشو تسير بسلاسة
I will go to Liuzhou personally
سأذهب إلى ليوتشو شخصيا
to help you gather private soldiers
لمساعدتك في جمع الجنود الخاصين
and contact all forces for more power.
واتصل بجميع القوى للحصول على المزيد من السلطة
Shiyu,
شيو
your trip to Liuzhou must be dangerous.
لا بد أن تكون رحلتك إلى ليوتشو خطيرة
I worry that...
أخشى أنه...
If the war between the two states really starts,
إذا بدأت الحرب بين المقاطعتين حقا
our people will suffer
شعبنا سوف يعاني
and our court will be turbulent.
ومحكمتنا ستكون مضطربة
More people will be victims.
المزيد من الناس سيكون ضحايا
I don't want to wait anymore.
لا أريد الانتظار بعد الآن
Shiyu, we need a more careful plan.
شيو، نحن بحاجة إلى خطة أكثر حذرا
(Benign and Benevolent)
(خير وخير)
Yueling, what is wrong?
يويل، ما هو الخطأ؟
You've been upset lately.
لقد كنت منزعجا في الآونة الأخيرة
I'm bored.
أشعر بالملل
Bored?
أشعر بالملل؟
Yueling, wait for me.
يويلينغ، انتظرني
Yueling, look.
يول، انظر
Look at this, Yueling.
انظري إلى هذا، يو لينغ
The wind blows.
الرياح تضرب
And this.
وهذا
This one is awesome.
هذا رائع
How about this? Look.
ماذا عن هذا؟ انظر
Oh, this.
أوه، هذا
Yueling,
يويل
what do think of this painting?
ما رأيك في هذه اللوحة؟
Is it Dongyu?
هل هو دونغيو؟
Yes.
نعم
I bought this painting
اشتريت هذه اللوحة
just because it looked so much like our hometown.
فقط لأنها بدت تشبه مسقط رأسنا بكثير
Yueling, you have no idea.
يويينغ، لا فكرة لديك
As far as I know,
على حد علمي
the painter is an extremely famous scholar
الرسام عالم مشهور للغاية
all over Beishuo.
في كل أنحاء بيشوه
He can play music, chess, and paint.
ويستطيع لعب الموسيقى والشطرنج والطلاء
All kinds of arts. Really perfect.
جميع أنواع الفنون، مثالية حقًا
Stories about him travel really fast.
سرعان ما ستنقل القصص عنه
Can someone really have such erudition?
هل يمكن لشخص أن يتقبل مثل هذه الحقيقة حقًا؟
Yes.
نعم
I hear every day, scholars visit Nanfeng House
أسمع كل يوم، يزور العلماء دار نانفنغ
where he is dwelling.
حيث يعيش
Even his door is thronged.
حتى بابه محاصر
I want to see him, too.
أريد أن أراه أيضًا
So do I.
إذًا أنا...
You want to see him?
هل تريد رؤيته؟
No time like the present.
لا وقت مثل الحاضر
Let's go now.
دعنا نذهب الآن
- Now? - Yes.
- الآن؟ - نعم
Fine, then.
حسنا، إذن
Yueling,
يويلينغ
Mr. Perfect who can do all kinds of arts
السيد بيرفيت الذي يمكنه ممارسة جميع أنواع الفنون
lives right here.
يعيش هنا
(Nanfeng House) I hear his paintings are worth a bundle.
(دار نانفنغ) سمعت أن لوماته تستحق حزم
Many dignitaries
العديد من الشخصيات
take pride in having his paintings.
يعتزمون الحصول على لوحته
A bundle?
حزم؟
How much did you spend?
كم أنفقت؟
Not very much.
ليس الكثير
Zhang, look at the lines.
تشانغ، انظر إلى الجمل
Quite vigorous.
قويا جدا
Indeed.
بالفعل
Impressive.
مذهل
What a lively place!
يا له من مكان حيوي!
I think these people
أعتقد أن هؤلاء الناس
all came here for Mr. Perfect.
جاء الجميع إلى هنا من أجل السيد بيرفكت
Mr. Perfect paints so perfectly
طلاءات السيد بيرفكت كاملة جدًا
with deep artistic conceptions.
لديه تصورات فنية عميقة
Yeah.
نعم
This Painting of Mountains
هذا الطين للجبال
vigorously portrayed verdant trees.
صورت بقوة الأشجار الغريبة
The mountains and trees rise layer upon layer.
الجبال والأشجار ترتفع طبقة تلو الأخرى
Really amazing.
مذهل حقا
Amazing.
رائعة
Good.
جيد
Look, the mountains are tall and big.
انظري، الجبال طويلة وكبيرة
The trees are numerous and dense.
الأشجار عديدة وكثافة
Really wonderful.
رائع حقا
Yueling,
يولت
since when could you comment on a painting?
منذ متى يمكنك التعليق على لوحة؟
They all comment here.
جميعهم يعلقون هنا
If we only watch instead of speaking,
إذا مراقبنا فقط بدلا من التحدث
we'll look rather ignorant.
سنبدو جاهلين بعض الشيء
That's right.
هذا صحيح
It's wise of you.
انه حكيم منك
This Painting of River
رسم النهر هذا
has a delicate and majestic composition.
لديه تكوين حساس ومهيب
Quite extraordinary.
استثنائية جدًا
- Yeah.
- نعم
Indeed.
بالفعل
Look at the river.
انظر إلى النهر
It's long and broad.
إنه طويل وواسع
That's right.
هذا صحيح
Look at the water. So much water.
انظري إلى الماء، الكثير من الماء
Isn't it brilliant?
أليس رائعًا؟
Can you even appreciate paintings?
هل يمكنك حتى تقدير اللوحات؟
What are you talking about?
عمّ تتحدث؟
Such a buzzkill.
يا لها من فوضى
Come on. Let's go somewhere else.
هيا، لنذهب إلى مكان آخر
Why?
لماذا؟
Your Grace, I think you have a good point.
غراسك، أعتقد أن لديك نقطة جيدة
It's all right.
لا بأس
Ignore them.
تجاهليها
They just don't appreciate paintings.
إنها فقط لا تقدر اللوحات الزيتية
Yeah.
نعم
So much water, indeed.
الكثير من الماء بالفعل
What are you laughing at?
ماذا تضحكين؟
Miss, you're quite interesting.
الآنسة، أنت مثيرة للاهتمام جدا
May I invite you
هل لي أن أدعوك
to have a talk in the tearoom?
لمخاطبة الحمام؟
Hey, who are you?
أنت؟
Why do you only invite my sister?
لماذا تدعو أختي فقط؟
Besides,
كما
we're here to see the famous Mr. Qin.
نحن هنا لرؤية السيد تشين الشهير
(Qin Siyuan, Mr. Perfect) I am Qin Siyuan.
(تشين سييوان، السيد بيرفكت) أنا تشين سيوان
So, you're Mr. Perfect?
لذلك، أنت السيد بيرفكت؟
Enjoy the tea, please.
استمتعا بالشاي من فضلك
Thanks.
شكرا
Mr. Perfect,
السيد بيرفيت
have you ever visited Dongyu?
هل قمت بزيارة دونغ يو؟
No.
لا
Then how did you paint
إذن كيف رسمت
the superb scenery of Dongyu?
مشهد دونغيو الرائع؟
Well,
إذن
I have something for reference.
لدي شيء كمرجع
There are also grasslands in Beishuo?
هناك أيضا مراعي في بيشوه؟
Mr. Perfect,
السيد بيرفيت
what did you use for reference
ماذا استخدمت للإشارة
to paint the same grassland in Dongyu?
لرسم نفس المراعي في دونغيو؟
Can you show me?
هل يمكنك أن تظهري لي؟
It's right in the backyard.
إنه في الفناء الخلفي
(Mild Weather and Bright Scenery)
(مشهد طقس الحليب واليمين)
Tent?
خيمة؟
Nest?
عش؟
I've never been to a grassland.
لم أذهب أبدا إلى مراعي
I just
أنا فقط
copied the scenery casually.
نسخت المشهد دون تكلف
What about the Painting of Mountains and the Painting of River?
ماذا عن رسم الجبال وطلاء النهر؟
(Mild Weather and Bright Scenery)
(طقس الحقل والتذكر)
This is the Painting of Mountains.
هذا هو تعليم الجبال
Here, the Painting of River.
هنا، رسم النهر
Well,
إذن
it's just a stinking ditch in my backyard.
إنها مجرد خدعة في فناء خلفي
Mr. Perfect, you're really special
السيد بيرفكت، أنت مميز جدًا
and creative.
ومبتكرة حقًا
You flatter me.
أنت تمازحني
Just some small tricks.
بعض الحيل الصغيرة فقط
Don't bother.
لا تتعبي نفسك
(Pleasant and Harmonious)
(النبل والوئام)
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Deliver this to the eastern yard.
قم بتوصيل هذا إلى الفناء الشرقي
I can't, Your Highness.
لا أستطيع يا صاحب السمو
Her Highness isn't in now.
صاحبة السمو ليست الآن
She isn't?
ليست كذلك؟
Where is she, then?
أين هي إذن؟
In Nanfeng House
في دار نانفنغ
where Mr. Qin Siyuan dwells.
حيث يعيش السيد تشين سييوان
Oh, Your Highness, do you know?
أوه، يا صاحب السمو، هل تعرف؟
Mr. Qin Siyuan
السيد تشين سييوان
is the most elegant young man in town.
هو الشباب الأكثر أناقة في المدينة
Her Highness is there for him.
صاحبة السمو هناك من أجله
Your Highness, you're just back.
صاحب السمو، لقد عدت فقط
Where are you going again?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب مرة أخرى؟
It's getting late.
تأخر الوقت
I'm going to get her back.
سأعيد إليها
Your Highness, wait for me.
صاحب السمو، انتظرني
Your Highness, you've just recovered.
صاحب السمو، لقد تعافيت للتو
Have more nutritious food.
تناول المزيد من الطعام المغذي
Before I think of a way
قبل أن أفكر في طريقة
to break up Zhou Shiyu and the Princess of Dongyu,
للفصل بين تشو شيوي وأميرة دونغيو
how can I be in the mood to eat?
كيف يمكنني أن أكون في مزاج مناسب لتناول الطعام؟
Take the dishes away.
خذي الأطباق بعيدا
Come on, Your Highness.
هيا يا صاحب السمو
Food is fuel for humans.
الطعام وقود للبشر
You have to eat something.
عليك أن تأكلي شيئًا
Wait, wait.
مهلًا
Look.
انظر
His Highness has lost weight.
لقد فقد سموه الوزن
Yeah, Your Highness.
نعم يا صاحب السمو
If you keep losing weight,
إذا واصلت فقدان الوزن
it'll be the neglect of our duty.
سيكون ذلك إهمال واجبنا
I've lost weight?
هل فقدت بعض الوزن؟
I can't let it be.
لا يمكنني السماح بهذا
My gorgeous face
وجهي الجميل
can't be harmed.
لا يمكن أن تتعرض للأذى
Get the dishes to me.
خذ الأطباق لي
Sure, Your Highness. Enjoy the food.
بالطبع يا صاحب السمو استمتع بالطعام
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
the Princess of Dongyu you asked us to keep an eye on
أميرة دونغيو لقد طلبت منا أن نراقب
went to Nanfeng House earlier today.
ذهبت إلى دار نانفنغ في وقت سابق اليوم
The North Prince went there, too.
ذهب الأمير الشمالي إلى هناك أيضا
They did?
هل فعلوا ذلك؟
Finally, I don't need to think hard
أخيرا، لا داعي لأن أفكر بجد
about how to break them up.
عن كيفية فصلهم
Zhou Shiyu,
تشو شيوي
you give me the chance.
أنت تمنحني الفرصة
Still eating?
مع تناول الطعام؟
What are you? A pig?
ماذا تفعل؟ خنزير؟
Let's get to business.
لنذهب إلى العمل
Girls, don't waste the food.
يا فتيات، لا تهدرن الطعام
Eat it up.
كلوه
Don't lose weight.
لا تفقدي الوزن
- Thank you, Your Highness.
- شكرا لك يا صاحب السمو
Your Highness, wait for me.
صاحب السمو، انتظرني
- Your Highness. - I'll eat this.
- صاحب السمو - سآكل هذا
(Nanfeng House)
(دار نانفنغ)
This painting is also made with the reference of my backyard.
هذه اللوحة أيضًا تتم بالإشارة إلى فناء خلفي
Actually, it's easy to paint.
في الحقيقة، من السهل الطلاء
If you're interested, Miss,
إذا كنت مهتمة، الآنسة
I can teach you.
أستطيع أن أعلمك
All right.
حسنًا
The paintings are good,
اللوحات جيدة
but they don't have souls.
لكن ليس لديها روحا
What are you doing here?
ماذا تفعل هنا؟
Different people enjoy various things.
الناس مختلفون يتمتعون بأشياء مختلفة
They just have different tastes.
لديهم فقط مذاق مختلف
You're right, Mr. Qin.
أنت على حق يا سيد تشين
You can have different tastes.
يمكنك أن يكون لديك مذاق مختلف
But you must not take away what someone else loves.
لكن يجب ألّا تأخذي ما يحبه الآخرون
Really?
حقًا؟
It's getting late.
الوقت متأخر
Let's get back home soon.
دعنا نعد إلى المنزل قريبا
Mr. Qin,
السيد تشين
that seems to be the carriage from the North Prince's mansion.
يبدو أن هذه هي العربة من قصر الأمير الشمالي
Who's that richly dressed man?
من ذلك الرجل الغني الثري؟
The North Prince.
أمير الشمال
Why did you pull me away?
لماذا سحبت لي؟
I wasn't done enjoying his paintings yet.
لم أنته من التمتع بلوماته بعد
His paintings are really...
لوحته هي حقًا...
Since when were you so interested in paintings?
منذ متى وأنت تهتمين بالصور؟
Why can't I be interested in paintings?
لماذا لا يمكنني أن أكون مهتمًا باللوحات؟
What are you actually interested in,
ما الذي تعنيه في الحقيقة
the paintings or the painter?
اللوحات أو الرسام؟
Mr. Perfect.
السيد بيرفكت
I'm really here to see the paintings.
أنا هنا حقا لرؤية اللوحات
The grassland he paints
المراعي التي يقوم طلاؤها
really looks like that in my hometown.
يبدو هكذا حقا في مسقط رأسي
See the painting?
أترين اللوحة؟
Then next, will you
إذن التالي، هل يمكنك
learn to paint from Mr. Perfect?
تعلم الطلاء من السيد بيرفكت؟
Yes.
نعم
I'll learn to paint from him.
سأتعلم الطلاء منه
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحياتي يا صاحب السمو
Don't stand on ceremony.
لا تقف في الحفل
You're still such a handsome painter.
ما زلت رسام وسيم
Nearly as handsome as me.
تقريبا وسيم مثلي
You flatter me, Your Highness.
أنت تمازحني يا صاحب السمو
Siyuan,
سيوان
recently,
مؤخرا
I've had a problem.
لقد لدي مشكلة
Your Highness, I'm indebted to you.
صاحب السمو، أنا مدين لك
So, I'm ready to help you.
لذلك، أنا مستعد لمساعدتك
Su Nian, that Dongyu man came again.
سو نيان، ذلك الرجل من دونغيو جاء مرة أخرى
Will you be dressed up again?
هل ستلبين مرة أخرى؟
No.
لا
That man is really weird.
هذا الرجل غريب جدًا
I don't know what he wants to do today,
لا أعرف ما يريد القيام به اليوم
watch a dance or do martial arts?
انتبه للرقص أم يمارس فنون الدفاع عن النفس؟
He's rather interesting, I think.
إنه مثير للاهتمام، في رأيي
Su Nian,
سو بيان
look what I’ve brought you.
انظري إلى ما أحضرتك به
Xingyi, what are these?
شينغ يي، ما هذه؟
Blade, spear, and sword.
رمح وسيف
Hammer and whip.
أطرنا وأطرقنا
Even a stick.
حتى عصا
Do I have to use all of them?
هل يتعين علي استخدامها جميعا؟
Yeah. To do great martial arts,
نعم للقيام بفنون الدفاع عن النفس عظيمة
you need a weapon you can use best.
أنت بحاجة إلى سلاح يمكنك استخدامه بشكل أفضل
Pick one.
اختاري سلاحًا
Thank you, then.
شكرًا لك إذن
What weapon do you use?
أي سلاح تستعمله؟
Me?
أنا؟
I don't need a weapon anymore.
لم أعد بحاجة إلى سلاح
Oh, Lingxi. You pick one, too.
أوه، لينغشي، اخترت واحدة أيضا
I can teach you.
أستطيع أن أعلمك
No, thanks.
لا، شكرًا
Obviously, there are too many kinds to choose from.
من الواضح أن هناك العديد من الأنواع للاختيار منها
Well, I'll leave the weapons here.
حسنًا، سأترك الأسلحة هنا
You take your time.
خذ وقتك
I should go back now.
يجب أن أعود الآن
Now?
الآن؟
Yes.
نعم
I had meant to teach you martial arts.
كنت أرغب في تعليمك فنون الدفاع عن النفس
But my sister invited Mr. Perfect
لكن أختي دعت السيد بيرفكت
to paint in our mansion.
للرسم في قصدنا
I have to go have a look.
يجب أن أذهب لإلقاء نظرة
Mr. Perfect.
السيد بيرفكت
Is it really a name for someone?
هل هو حقا اسم لشخص ما؟
Yes.
نعم
The one living in Nanfeng House.
الشخص الذي يعيش في دار نانفنغ
Mr. Qin Siyuan, huh?
السيد تشين سييوان، هوه؟
Yes, it's him.
نعم، إنه هو
Now, he's my sister's art teacher.
الآن، إنه معلم الفنون في أختي
Mr. Qin's paintings are indeed marvelous.
لوحات السيد تشين مذلة بالفعل
I admire him a lot.
أنا معجب به كثيرا
But I haven't got a chance to consult him.
لكنني لم تتح لي الفرصة للتشاور معه
You also want to see him?
هل تريد رؤيته أيضًا
That's easy.
هذا سهل
Count on me.
أعتمد علي
(Everything is going smoothly.)
(كل شيء يسير بسلاسة)
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
What?
ماذا؟
Her Highness's yard is lively again.
فناء صاحبة السمو حيوي مرة أخرى
Is she drunk again?
هل هي ثملة مرة أخرى؟
No.
لا
Oh, good.
أوه، جيد
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
Her Highness is learning to paint from Mr. Qin.
تعلم الطلاء من السيد تشين
Learning to paint?
تعلم الطلاء؟
Her Highness paints so well, huh?
صاحبة السمو الطلاءات جيدا، هوه؟
Impressive, isn't it?
مثيرة للإعجاب، أليس كذلك؟
- Yes.
- نعم
Great, isn't it?
رائع، أليس كذلك؟
Her Highness is really talented.
صاحبة السمو موهوبة حقا
Xingyi,
شينغ يي
why are you painting a tilting tree?
لماذا طلاء شجرة حرث؟
This tree
هذه الشجرة
is just tilting in the wind.
تميل فقط في الرياح
I think Mr. Xingyi's tree
أعتقد أن شجرة السيد شينغ يي
is nearly blown away by the wind.
تقريبا تنهيها الرياح
Wonderful. Wonderful indeed.
رائع، رائع بالفعل
You have such a good eye for it.
لديك عين جيدة لذلك
Miss Su Nian, you paint so beautifully.
سو نيان، أنت ترسم صورة جميلة جدًا
Your tree looks good, too.
تبدو شجرة الخاصة بك جميلة أيضًا
You use easy lines,
تستخدم خطوط سهلة
but it gives an exquisite refinement.
لكنها تقدم تنقيحا رائعا
- Of course.
- بالطبع
Speaking of refinement,
بالحديث عن التنقيح
no one can do better than me.
لا أحد أفضل مني
The South Prince is here.
الأمير الجنوبي هنا
Don't bother to greet me.
لا تتعبي نفسك تحياتي
You may go on.
لنذهب
Your Highness?
سموك؟
What are you doing here?
ماذا تفعل هنا؟
I hear you love to paint lately.
أسمعك تحب الطلاء في الآونة الأخيرة
Then, I have to come.
إذن، يجب أن آتي
In Beishuo, speaking of painters,
في بيشوه تحدث عن رسامين
Qin...
تشين...
Mr. Qin is the best.
السيد تشين هو الأفضل
Then I'm only second to him.
إذن أنا ثانيا له
You can paint?
يمكنك الطلاء؟
What are you talking about?
عمّ تتحدث؟
Xingyi, come on. Hurry.
شينغ يي، هيا، بسرعة
Look at this.
انظري إلى هذا
Look at the chick.
انظري إلى الطبق
Is it actually a hen?
هل هو في الحقيقة رهين؟
He said Mr. Qin was the best painter
قال إن السيد تشين كان أفضل رسام
and he was the second best.
وكان ثاني أفضل طالب
He really bragged.
لقد تفاخر حقًا
It looks awful.
يبدو فظيعًا
Don't laugh.
لا تضحك
You have no taste at all.
ليس لديك ذوق على الإطلاق
Go away.
ابتعد
I painted it with utmost effort.
رسمتها بأقصى جهد
I named it,
سميتها
the Painting of Eagle.
طبخ النخيل
Mr. Qin, what do you
السيد تشين، ماذا ترى
think of this painting?
في هذه اللوحة؟
Wonderful.
رائع
Wonderful, indeed.
رائع بالفعل
Mr. Qin, did you see his painting?
السيد تشين، هل رأيت لوحته؟
Wonderful.
رائع
Wait.
انتظر
That's what you just said about my painting.
هذا ما قلته للتو عن لوحتي
Your Highness, the South Prince is here.
صاحب السمو، الأمير الجنوبي هنا
I saw him.
لقد رأيته
Shall we go have a look?
هل نذهب لإلقاء نظرة
Mr. Qin said my painting was wonderful.
قال السيد تشين إن لوحتي رائعة
My painting
لوحتي
isn't like your poor ones.
لا تشبه الفقيرة منهم
Hey, what's your look?
ما هذه مظهرك
Mr. Qin, look at her painting.
سيد تشين، انظر إلى لوحتها
A boring painting of the landscape.
لوحة جميلة من المشهد
And this tilting tree...
وهذه الشجرة المربحة...
Awful.
مريعة
This...
هذه...
A bald tree.
شجرة أصلع
So pale.
شاحبة جدًا
- What are you talking about?
- عمّ تتحدثين؟ - عم تتحدثين؟ - ما الذي تتحدث عنه؟
- Can't you comment nicely?
- ألا يمكنك التعليق بشكل جميل؟
- What a man! - Then don't comment.
- يا له من رجل! - يا له من رجل! - إذن لا تعلق
Your...
...
Your wild eagle is fierce-looking.
نسرك البري يبدو كأسًا
Wonderful, huh?
رائع يا هو؟
But look closely.
لكن انظري عن كثب
This isn't an eagle.
هذا ليس نسرًا
This is actually a chick.
هذه نزهة في الحقيقة
That's right.
هذا صحيح
And look down here. Some rice.
وألق نظرة هنا، بعض الأرز
I think
أعتقد
it should be Chick Pecking at the Rice.
يجب أن يكون تشق الأرز
Chick Pecking at the Rice!
تشك في الأرز!
Oh, Chick Pecking at the Rice!
نعم، تشك في الأرز!
Where is Zhou Shiyu?
أين تشو شي يو؟
Get him to me.
خذه لي
- Oh, Chick Pecking at the Rice!
- يا إلهي! تشق الأرز! - تشك في الأرز!
Where is he?
أين هو؟
Zhou Shiyu,
تشو شي يو
can't you see your brother is here?
ألا ترى أخوك هنا؟
- Oh, Chick Pecking at the Rice!
- يا إلهي! تشق الأرز! - يا إلهي! تشك في الأرز!
(Account Book)
(دفتر الحسابات)
Prime Minister.
رئيس الوزراء
Good.
جيد
Good job.
أحسنت صنعًا
Very good.
جيد جدا
Any word from Nan Xun?
أي كلمة من نان شيون؟
No trace of illegal weapons has been found.
لم يتم العثور على أي أثر للأسلحة غير المشروعة
Nan Xun stalks them for a while,
نان شيون يطاردها لفترة من الوقت
only to find they make iron ore just for sale.
فقط للعثور على ركاز الحديد للبيع فقط
If the North Prince only makes iron ore
إذا كان الأمير الشمالي ينتج ركاز الحديد فقط
to accumulate wealth,
تراكم الثروة
we don't need to fear.
ليس علينا أن نخشى
It's still too early
لا يزال من المبكر جدا
to come to this conclusion.
للوصول إلى هذا الاستنتاج
Go.
اذهب
Ask Yang Xu to stick to our plan.
اطلب من يانغ شو أن يتقيد بخطتنا
Yes.
نعم
Great.
رائع
Awesome.
رائعة
Really awesome!
رائعة حقًا!
(Hall of Politics)
"قاعة السياسة"
(Memorial to the Throne, Account Book)
(التقديم إلى العرش، كتاب الحسابات)
Recently, I've received a letter of accusation.
في الآونة الأخيرة، تلقيت رسالة اتهام
Reading it, I felt bitterly disappointed
قرأتها، شعرت بخيبة أمل كبيرة
and utterly shocked.
وصدمت بشدة
I have to present it to you, Your Majesty.
يجب أن أقدمها لك يا صاحب الجلالة
(Memorial to the Throne, Account Book)
(ذكرى العرش، كتاب الحسابات)
His Highness held an account book, I think.
كان لسموه كتاب حساب، أعتقد
You're sharp-eyed, censor.
أنت حاصل على رقيب
But this isn't an ordinary account book,
لكن هذا ليس دفتر حسابات عادي
but something that can show the North Prince's intention
ولكن شيئا يمكن أن يظهر نية الأمير الشمالي
of rebellious schemes.
من مخططات التمرد
Rebellious schemes?
مخططات التمرد؟
Oh, rebellion.
تمرد
That's a capital offense.
هذه جريمة عاصمة
In Taizhou and Yingzhou, the North Prince
في تاتشو وينغتشو، الأمير الشمالي
makes illegal iron ore and forge weapons.
ينتج ركاز الحديد غير القانوني ويصنع الأسلحة
He wants to rebel.
يريد التمرد
(Memorial to the Throne)
(نصب تذكاري العرش)
North Prince,
الأمير الشمالي
is that true?
هل هذا صحيح؟
For your information, Brother,
لإبلاغك يا أخي
I do have two illegal iron mines.
لدي اثنان من الحديد غير القانوني
But I don't have them for illegal weapons.
لكن ليس لدي هذه الأسلحة للأسلحة غير المشروعة
In recent years, actually,
في الحقيقة
I've been overspending.
تجاوزت في الإنفاق
So, I want more money for living expenses.
لذا، أريد المزيد من المال لمصروفات المعيشة
Nonsense.
هراء
If you need money,
إذا كنت بحاجة إلى المال
you can do many other businesses.
يمكنك القيام بالكثير من الأعمال التجارية الأخرى
Why do you do the iron mining
لماذا تقوم باستخراج الحديد
that is expressly forbidden?
وهذا محظور صراحة؟
South Prince, don't you also
الأمير الجنوبي، أليس كذلك
do illegal salt trades?
تجارة الملح غير المشروعة؟
Why can you do an illegal business
لماذا يمكنك القيام بأعمال تجارية غير مشروعة
while I can't?
بينما لا أستطيع؟
I do illegal salt trades for money
تجارة الملح غير المشروعة مقابل المال
while you want to rebel.
بينما تريد التمرد
They're totally different things.
إنها أشياء مختلفة تمامًا
So, you admit you do illegal salt trades?
إذًا تعترف بأنك تتاجر بالملح بشكل غير قانوني؟
You...
أنت...
Zhou Shiyu, you set me up?
تشو شيوي، هل قمت بإعداد لي؟
I shouldn't have done the same thing
ما كان ينبغي لي أن أفعل الشيء نفسه
as the South Prince just to get more money.
كأمير الجنوب فقط للحصول على المزيد من المال
I deserve any punishment.
أستحق أي عقوبة
Your Majesty,
صاحب الجلالة
please punish the South Prince and me.
يرجى معاقبة الأمير الجنوبي وأنا
Zhou Shiyu,
تشو شي يو
don't get me involved.
لا تتورط بي
Shiyu confessed his sin.
اعترف شيو خطيئته
Chenyu, you still deny it?
تشينيو، هل ما زلت تنكر ذلك؟
I can confess.
يمكنني أن أعترف
But I'm only greedy for money.
لكنني جشعة فقط للمال
A small punishment will do.
عقاب صغير سيفي بالغرض
But the North Prince wants to rebel.
لكن الأمير الشمالي يريد التمرد
And here is the evidence of his illegal iron mines.
وهذا هو الدليل على مناجم الحديد غير القانونية الخاصة به
Brother, do punish him for treason.
أخي، يعاقب عليه بالخيانة
Brother is wise enough to decide.
الأخ حكيم بما فيه الكفاية لاتخاذ القرار
Or do you want to usurp his authority
أم أنك تريد اغتصاب سلطته
and make a decision for him?
واتخاذ قرار نيابة عنه؟
In contrast,
في المقابل
it's really obvious which of us
من الواضح حقا من منا
wants to rebel.
من يريد التمرد
Don't try to implicate me.
لا تحاول توريط
You implicated me first.
لقد تورطتني أولًا
- You... - Enough.
- أنت... - كفى
My brothers,
إخوتي
look at you.
انظري لنفسك
One does illegal salt trades
أحدهم يقوم بعمليات الملح غير المشروعة
while the other has illegal iron mines.
في حين أن الآخر لديه مناجم حديدية غير مشروعة
As important officials,
كمسؤولين مهمين
how could you make such mistakes
كيف يمكنك ارتكاب مثل هذه الأخطاء
just for selfish desires?
فقط من أجل رغبات أنانية؟
For the sake it's your first crime,
من أجل أنها أول جريمة لك
you'll each get 50 floggings in the Ministry of Punishments
ستحصل كل واحدة منها على 50 جلدة في وزارة العقوبات
and your salary of six months will be deducted.
وسيتم خصم راتبك لمدة ستة أشهر
- But Brother, I... - Duly noted, Brother.
- لكن أخي، أنا... - فهمت بشكل صحيح يا أخي
I accept the punishments.
أقبل العقوبات
Duly noted, Your Majesty.
أمرك، يا صاحب الجلالة
I accept the punishments, too.
أقبل العقوبات أيضا
Your Grace.
غريسك
Your...
أنت...
Take it easy. Slow down.
لا ترهقي، تمهلي
The North Prince...
الأمير الشمالي...
He was reported by the South Prince
أبلغ عنه الأمير الجنوبي
for the account book or the rebel thing.
من أجل دفتر الحسابات أو شيء التمرد
Anyway, His Majesty had him flogged.
على أي حال، جلد جلالة الإمبراطور
Account book?
دفتر الحساب؟
Your Grace, what are you looking for?
غريسة، ماذا تبحث عنه؟
This is where I kept the account book.
هذا هو المكان الذي احتفظت فيه بحسابات
Why is it gone?
لماذا اختفى؟
How... How come?
كيف... كيف تأتي؟
Oh, no.
لا
The account book must be the reason.
لا بد أن كتاب الحسابات هو السبب
Who on earth stole it?
من سرقته بحق السماء؟
(Pleasant and Harmonious)
(ناضج ومتسق)
Your Highness, shortly after the use of the ointment,
صاحب السمو، بعد فترة قصيرة من استخدام المرهم
your hips bleed again.
نزفت قبائلك مرة أخرى
It must hurt a lot.
لا بد أنها تؤلمك كثيرًا
It doesn't matter.
لا يهم
The executor in the Ministry of Punishments
المنفذ في وزارة العقوبات
is really merciless.
لا رحمة حقا
He flogged you so hard.
جلّدك بقوة
If he hadn't,
لو لم يكن كذلك
how could Uncle believe this?
كيف يمكن عمي أن يصدق هذا؟
Shiyu.
شيو
Hearing you're injured,
سمعت أنك مصابة
I came
جئت
with the best ointment.
أفضل مرهم
Thank you.
شكرًا لك
Shiyu, are you still mad at me?
شيو هل أنت مجنون مني؟
I was too childish before.
كنت طفوليًا جدًا من قبل
Shiyu, you don't feel very well today.
شيو، أنت لا تشعرين بالراحة اليوم
Don't get angry with me.
لا تغضب مني
Shiyu, this is the special ointment from the south of the Five Ridges.
شيو هذا هو المرهم الخاص من جنوب الروايات الخمس
It promotes blood circulation perfectly.
إنها تعزز الدوران الدم بشكل مثالي
(I don't think he needs my ointment.)
(لا أعتقد أنه بحاجة إلى مربي)
Your Highness?
صاحبة السمو؟
Why didn't get in, Your Highness?
لماذا لم تدخل يا صاحبة السمو؟
I was just about to get in.
كنت على وشك الدخول
What about Your Highness?
ماذا عن سموك؟
How is he now?
كيف حاله الآن؟
Look.
انظر
A mass of blood.
كتلة من الدم
I can't help feeling sorry.
لا يسعني أن أشعر بالأسف
Princess Luoyi brought some ointment.
أحضرت الأميرة لويي بعض المرهم
Your Highness, Her Highness is here.
صاحبة السمو، صاحبة السمو هنا
Get her in.
اركبها
Your Highness, His Highness is waiting for you.
سموك، سموه ينتظرك
You just get in.
أنت تدخل فحسب
All right.
حسنًا
Oh, my future cousin-in-law.
زوج ابنة عمي المستقبلي
My cousin is so badly injured.
ابن عمي مصاب بجروح بليغة
What took you so long?
ما الذي أخّرك؟
Does it still hurt?
هل ما زال مؤلمًا؟
Look at him.
انظري إليه
How does it not hurt?
كيف لا يؤلمك؟
Also,
وأيضًا
I'm talking to you.
أنا أتحدث إليك
Why do you not reply?
لماذا لا تجيبين؟
Luoyi,
لوييي
it's getting late.
إن الوقت متأخر
You should get back to the palace.
يجب أن تعود إلى القصر
Shiyu, let me stay tonight.
شيو، دعني أبقى الليلة
Then I can take care of you.
إذن يمكنني الاعتناء بك
You just go.
اذهبي فحسب
- I have... - He has me.
- لديّ... - - لديّ
You'd better leave early, Luoyi.
من الأفضل أن تغادر باكرًا يا لويي
It's getting late, after all.
الوقت تأخر، بعد كل شيء
You...
أنت...
How can you stay with him?
كيف يمكنك البقاء معه؟
Why can't I?
لماذا لا يمكنني ذلك؟
I'm his bride-to-be.
أنا عفريت له
That's right.
هذا صحيح
She'll take care of me.
سوف تعتني بي
You don't need to worry.
لا داعي للقلق
Linmu.
لنمو
Walk Princess Luoyi back to the palace.
اسير الأميرة لويي للعودة إلى القصر
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم يا صاحب السمو
There you go, Your Grace.
ها أنت ذي يا ملك
I'll count on you, Your Highness.
سأعتمد عليك يا صاحب السمو
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
Your Highness, I'll be gentle.
صاحب السمو، سأكون لطيفا
The flogging didn't kill me.
الجلد لم يقتلني
But you nearly did.
لكنك فعلت ذلك تقريبا
His Highness is miserable.
سموه بائس
Your Highness.
سموك
Be gentle.
كن لطيفا
Yang Xu, get out of here.
يانغ شو، اخرج من هنا
It's all because of your awful idea.
هذا كله بسبب فكرتك المريعة
My brother has never flogged me before.
لم يجبرني أخي أبدا من قبل
Don't be angry, Your Highness.
لا تغضب يا صاحب السمو
This is the ointment for blood circulation.
هذا هو المرهم للدورة الدموية
You have to bear the paint.
عليك أن تحمل الطلاء
Out there, I have to bear Zhou Shiyu.
هناك، يجب أن أتحمل تشو شيوي
Back at home, I still have to bear.
للعودة إلى المنزل، لا يزال يجب أن أتحمل
Why?
لماذا؟
Be gentle!
لطيف!
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Yueling, what are you thinking?
يينغ، ماذا تفكرين؟
It must be hurting a lot.
يجب أن يكون مؤلما كثيرا
Yeah.
نعم
My brother showed no mercy.
لا يرحم أخي
(Healing)
(الشفاء)
Yueling, you brought me some ointment, huh?
يويلينغ، لقد أحضرت لي بعض المرهم، هوه؟
No.
لا
(Healing ointment) So, is this ointment
(غسل المرهم) لذلك، هل هذا المرهم
not for me?
ليس لي؟
It's for you.
إنه لك
But it's just an ordinary ointment.
لكنها مجرد مرهم عادي
Not as good as what Princess Luoyi gave you.
ليس جيدًا مثل ما أعطيتك إياه الأميرة لوي
But I think this is the best.
لكنني أعتقد أن هذا أفضل
Sorry.
آسف
I failed to keep the account book.
فشلت في مسك دفتر الحساب
So, you were reported and flogged.
لذلك، تم الإبلاغ عنك وجلدك
You also planned to report me, didn't you?
كما خططت للإبلاغ عني، أليس كذلك؟
I didn't know you were the North Prince.
لم أكن أعلم أنك الأمير الشمالي
If I had known that,
لو كنت أعرف ذلك
I wouldn't have tried to report you.
ما كنت لأحاول إبلاغك
If it was me,
إذا كنت أنا
you would never turn me in, right?
لن تديرني أبدًا، صحيح؟
Come on.
هيا
I'm all right.
أنا بخير
I don't blame you.
أنا لا ألومك
♪Clouds slowly float across the sky♪
♪ الغيوم تطفو ببطء عبر السماء ♪
♪Telling what is awfully bothering♪
♪ وضع ما يزعج كثيرا ♪
♪Ceaseless, love lingers and lingers♪
♪ لا يتوقف، أحب الأمور المتبقية والدائمة ♪
♪You and I both know it♪
♪ أنا وأنت نعرف ذلك ♪
♪In this world, we stay side by side♪
♪ في هذا العالم، نبقى جنبا إلى جنب ♪
♪Watching the stars rise and fall♪
♪ مشاهدة النجوم ترتفع وتنخفض ♪
♪My eyes are red from missing you♪
♪ عيني أحمر من غيابكم ♪
♪Tonight, I hope the moonlight will♪
♪ ليلة، آمل أن يكون ضوء القمر ♪
♪Kiss your eyebrows♪
♪ قبلة حاجباك ♪
♪I'll always be in love with you♪
♪ سأكون دائمًا في حبك ♪
♪Promising it'll last forever♪
♪ مؤشر على أنها ستدوم إلى الأبد ♪
♪As the breeze blows, the flower fades♪
♪ مع ضربات النسيم، تتلاشى الزهرة ♪
♪Leaving a wish to be fulfilled♪
♪ إنقاذ أمنية يتعين تحقيقها ♪
♪To have joy for the rest of its life♪
♪ للفخر لبقية حياتها ♪
♪I'll stay with you for thousands of years♪
♪ سأبقى معك بآلاف السنين ♪
♪Until we grow old together♪
♪ حتى نتقدم في السن معا ♪
♪As the breeze blows, the flower fades♪
♪ كما ضربات النسيم، تتلاشى الزهرة ♪
♪When I look back, you whisper♪
♪ عندما أنظر إلى الوراء، أنت أتذمر ♪
♪Then I wake up from the dream♪
♪ إذن أستيقظ من الحلم ♪
♪Like how we met for the first time♪
♪ مثل كيفية التقينا للمرة الأولى ♪